http://www.southdownsheepsociety.co.uk/privacy-notice

Minimum standard and recommendations
PRIVACY NOTICEThis Privacy Notice explains the types of personal data we may collect about you when you interact with us. It also explains how we will store and handle this data and keep it safe.The Southdown Sheep Society is a Company Limited by Guarantee and a Registered Charity.  The objects of the Society are to promote for the benefit of the public the conservation, protection and improvement of the physical and natural environment by promoting biological diversity through the promotion and registration of Southdown sheep.  The Society has power to do anything calculated to further the objects, or is conducive or incidental to doing so, including inter alia:i.      the maintenance and publication of a flock book of registered and pedigree sires and ewes, andii.     the periodical compilation and publication of information connected with the breed such as particulars relating to shows and sales. The Legal Bases we rely on:The law on data protection sets out a number of different reasons for which a company may collect and process your personal data.Legitimate interestIn relation to members of the Southdown Sheep Society we require your data to pursue our legitimate interests in a way which might reasonably be expected as part of running our business and which does not materially impact your rights, freedoms or interests.ConsentIn specific circumstances we can collect and process your data with your consent.Contractual obligationsIn certain circumstances we need your personal data to comply with our contractual obligations.Legal complianceIf the law requires us to do so, we may need to collect and process your data. When do we collect your personal data?*When you join the Society as a member*When members register births, sales and purchases of sheep*When you exhibit sheep at agricultural shows*When you purchase a product from us*When you contact us by any means with enquiries, complaints etc.*When we engage you to provide goods or services What sort of personal data do we collect?*For members we collect: your name, address, date of birth ( if under 18 years of age), holding number (CPH number), UK Flock Number, email and telephone numbers, bank account details, details of sheep bred, bought and sold, copies of correspondence with you.*for suppliers we collect: your name, contact details, payment details, contract information.*for purchasers of goods we collect:  your name, address, contact details, payment details.*photographs of exhibitors of Southdown sheep appearing in public at agricultural shows and Society events. How and why do we use your personal data?In pursuit of our legitimate interests we publish a flock book detailing pedigree Southdown sheep and their breeders, an on-line database of all pedigree Southdown sheep, their breeders and owners, a Year Book, periodic newsletters, and other publications aimed at promoting the Southdown breed.Data on suppliers of goods and services to the Society and of purchasers from the Society is used for the processing of transactions and the management of contracts.Your data is held in the Southdown office and is managed and controlled by the Secretary of the Society.  The data may also be accessed by the officers and other members of the Society’s Council.Lists of members with contact details may also be provided to regional representatives/co-ordinators of the Society in connection with the organisation of local events. How do we protect your personal data?Your personal data is protected in the following ways:password protection of Pedewebsecurity in the officewitholding email addresses on bulk emailingsregional co-ordinators adhere to security measures and delete all data once used for the single purpose of contacting regional group members How long will we keep your personal data?Personal data will only be kept as long as it is necessary for the purpose for which it was collected.  At the end of the retention period it will either be deleted or anonymised.As the object of the Society depends on the production of a historic record of pedigrees some published material, for example the Flock Book, will be maintained for posterity.Who do we share your personal data with?We sometimes share data with trusted third parties, for example IT companies who support our website and business systems, and our auditors.  In all cases we apply the following policy:*We provide only the information they need to perform their specific services.*They may only use your data for the exact purposes we specify to them.*We work closely with them to ensure your privacy is respected and protected at all time.*If we stop using their services any of your data held by them will be deleted or rendered anonymous.We will not share your data with third parties for their own purposes, except when we receive a valid request from a law enforcement body.We will not share your data with third parties or suppliers outside the European Economic Area.What are your rights over your personal data?You have the right to request:*Access to the personal data we hold about you, free of charge in most cases.*The correction of your personal data when it is incorrect, out of date or incomplete.*That we stop any consent based processing of your personal data after you withdraw that consent.Members under 18 years oldIt is necessary to record the date of birth of any members under 18 years of age. This information will be collected in the future from new members, but for the small number of under-18 members currently on our database, please contact the office with your date of birth so that this information can be recorded.To exercise these rights please contact:The Secretary, Southdown Sheep Society, Meens Farm, Capps Lane, All Saints, Halesworth, Suffolk IP19 0PD.   secretary@southdownsheepsocietyco.ukThe Society has chosen not to appoint a Data Protection Officer as it is not a public authority and the core activities do not require large scale, regular and systematic monitoring of individuals nor large scale processing of special categories or of data relating to criminal convictions or offences.1st May 2018
Email: secretary@southdownsheepsociety.co.ukTel: 01986 782251
